<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Centauri</string>

    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>
    <string name="learn">Learn</string>
    <string name="news">News</string>
    <string name="profile">Profile</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">open</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">close</string>

        <!--    BASIC SETTING STRINGS    -->

    <string name="unauthenticated">Guest</string>
    <string name="sign_in">Sign in</string>
    <string name="sign_out">Sign out</string>
    <string name="language_settings">Language Settings</string>
    <string name="you_are_not_authenticated">You are not authenticated</string>
    <string name="have_to_create_account">You have to create an account for this!</string>


    <!--//////////   MESSAGES     //////////-->

    <string name="start_test">Start a test? 🚀</string>
    <string name="take_test_description">Take a test based on what you’ve learned and check your understanding of the material.
    If you pass, the next section will be unlocked for you to study.</string>

    <string name="lesson_closed">This lesson is closed</string>
    <string name="fail_to_get_data">Sorry but it seems the app failed to get your data from Database Please try later</string>
    <string name="error">ERROR</string>

    <string name="correct">Correct!</string>
    <string name="incorrect">Incorrect!</string>

    <string name="sth_went_wrong">Something went wrong</string>

    <!-- Lesson Messages   -->
    <string name="loading_question">Loading question...</string>
    <string name="checking_ai">Checking is AI working...</string>
    <string name="ai_not_working">Sorry the AI assistence is not working Try later</string>




    <!--//////////    The lesson structure ////////// -->
    <string name="part_1">Introduction to Astronomy</string>
    <string name="lesson1">The Nature of Astronomy and Science</string>
    <string name="lesson2">The Universe: Large and Small Scales</string>
    <string name="lesson3">Observing the Sky: History of Astronomy</string>
    <string name="lesson4">Tools of Astronomy: Telescopes &amp; Instruments</string>

    <string name="part_2">The Solar System &amp; Its Components</string>
    <string name="lesson5">Orbits &amp; Gravity: The Foundation</string>
    <string name="lesson6">The Earth-Moon System</string>
    <!--    <string name="lesson7">The Inner Planets (Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars)</string>-->
    <string name="lesson7">The Planets (inner, outer, exo)</string>
    <string name="lesson8">The Outer Planets &amp; Beyond</string>


    <string name="part_3"> The Sun &amp; Stars</string>
    <string name="lesson9">The Sun as a Star</string>
    <string name="lesson10">Stellar Classification &amp; Spectroscopy</string>
    <string name="lesson11"> Life Cycles of Stars</string>
    <string name="lesson12">Supernovae, Neutron Stars &amp; Black Holes</string>

    <string name="part_4">  Galaxies &amp; Cosmology</string>
    <string name="lesson13">The Milky Way Galaxy</string>"
    <string name="lesson14">Types of Galaxies &amp; Their Evolution</string>
    <string name="lesson15"> Dark Matter &amp; The Expanding Universe</string>
    <string name="lesson16">The Big Bang &amp; The Fate of the Universe</string>


    <!--===============   LESSONS STARTS HERE  =============== -->

    <!--    lesson 1    -->
    <string name="lesson1_title_1">What is Astronomy?</string>
    <string name="lesson1_text_1">Astronomy is the study of everything beyond Earth—planets, stars,
        galaxies, and the vast universe itself. It is one of the oldest sciences,
        dating back thousands of years when ancient civilizations first gazed at the night sky,
        tracking the movements of celestial objects. Early astronomers used the Sun, Moon, and stars to measure time,
        predict seasons, and navigate across oceans. The Babylonians created some of the earliest star maps over 5,000 years ago,
        the Egyptians aligned their pyramids with certain stars, and the Greeks developed early models of the solar system.
        The Mayans were able to predict solar and lunar eclipses,
        while scholars during the Islamic Golden Age made major contributions to astronomical calculations.
        Over time, as technology advanced, our understanding of the universe expanded.
        Today, powerful telescopes allow us to see distant galaxies billions of light-years away,
        while space probes explore planets and moons in our solar system.
        But even with all this progress, astronomy remains a science of endless discovery,
        helping us understand not only where we are in the universe but also how everything came to be.
    </string>

    <string name="lesson1_title_2">Our Solar System</string>
    <string name="lesson1_text_2">
        Our home, Earth, is just one small part of a much larger cosmic neighborhood called the solar system.
        At its center is the Sun, a massive ball of hot gas that provides the energy needed for life on our planet.
        Surrounding it are eight planets—Mercury, Venus, Earth, Mars, Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune—each unique in size,
        composition, and atmosphere. Some planets, like Earth and Mars, have solid surfaces,
        while others, like Jupiter and Saturn, are made mostly of gas. Beyond the planets, there are moons, asteroids,
        comets, and dwarf planets like Pluto, all of which play an important role in our cosmic system. </string>

    <string name="lesson1_title_3">The Nearest Star: Proxima Centauri</string>
    <string name="lesson1_text_3">
        Our solar system is just a tiny part of the Milky Way Galaxy,
        which contains billions of stars. The closest star beyond our Sun is Proxima Centauri, part of the Alpha Centauri system
        , located 4.3 light-years away. Though this is the nearest star,
        traveling there with current technology would take thousands of years.
        Scientists are especially interested in Proxima Centauri because it has a planet, Proxima b, which might have conditions
        suitable for life. This makes it an important target for future space exploration,
        and its name has become a symbol of humanity’s curiosity about the universe.
    </string>

    <string name="lesson1_title_4">Why Astronomy is Important</string>

    <string name="lesson1_text_4">
        Astronomy is more than just stargazing—it impacts many areas of life:\n\

        Technology: Many innovations, like GPS and cameras in smartphones, were developed from astronomical research.\n\
        Climate Science: Studying planets like Venus helps us understand global warming.\n\
        Space Exploration: Helps us prepare for future space travel and asteroid defense.\n\
    </string>


    <!--    lesson 2    -->
    <string name="lesson2_title">The Universe – Large and Small Scales</string>
    <string name="lesson2_title_1">The Universe – Large and Small Scales</string>
    <string name="lesson2_text_1">Astronomy helps us understand not only Earth and our solar system but also the vastness of the universe itself.
        The universe is everything that exists—space, time, matter, and energy. It is so immense that even the fastest thing we know, light,
        takes billions of years to travel across it. The universe contains hundreds of billions of galaxies, each filled with billions of stars and planets.
        Our own galaxy, the Milky Way, is just one of these countless cosmic structures.
        But despite its enormous size, the universe is also made up of the tiniest things imaginable,
        such as atoms, subatomic particles, and even mysterious forces like dark matter and dark energy.
        Scientists believe that the universe began with the Big Bang about 13.8 billion years ago,
        a moment when everything we see today was once packed into an incredibly small, hot, and dense state before expanding outward.
        This expansion is still happening, meaning the universe is growing every second.
        Even though our planet may seem big to us, in the grand scale of the cosmos, Earth is just a tiny speck.
    </string>

    <string name="lesson2_title_2">Galaxies, Stars, and Planets</string>
    <string name="lesson2_text_2">
        Galaxies, stars, and planets exist on incredibly large scales that are hard to imagine. A single galaxy can stretch over hundreds of thousands of light-years and contain billions or even trillions of stars.
Our own galaxy, the Milky Way, is about 100,000 light-years wide, and that’s just one of billions of galaxies in the universe. Stars, the building blocks of galaxies, also vary greatly in size—some are
several times larger than our Sun, while others are much smaller. The Sun itself is so massive that about 1.3 million Earths could fit inside it. Planets, in comparison, are much smaller, but still impressive in size.
For example, Jupiter is the largest planet in our solar system and is more than 11 times wider than Earth. These enormous differences in scale—from planets to stars to galaxies—show just how vast and varied
the universe really is. </string>

    <string name="lesson2_title_3">The Smallest Structures in the Universe</string>
    <string name="lesson2_text_3">
        While the universe is unimaginably vast, it is also made up of incredibly tiny building blocks.
        Everything we see, from planets to people, is made up of atoms, which are themselves made of protons, neutrons, and electrons.
        But scientists have discovered even smaller particles, such as quarks and neutrinos, that help explain the fundamental nature of matter.
        Even more mysterious are dark matter and dark energy—two invisible forces that make up most of the universe but are still not fully understood.
        Dark matter is thought to provide the unseen mass that holds galaxies together, while dark energy is believed
        to be responsible for the accelerating expansion of the universe. These discoveries show that there is still
        so much left to learn about the universe, both on the largest scales and the smallest.
        Studying these extremes helps scientists unlock the mysteries of space and understand our place in the cosmos.
    </string>


    <!--    lesson 3    -->
    <string name="lesson3_title">Observing the Sky: History of Astronomy</string>

    <string name="lesson3_title_1">The Origins of Astronomy</string>
    <string name="lesson3_text_1">
Since the beginning of civilization, humans have looked up at the sky, fascinated by the Sun, Moon, and stars.
Astronomy is one of the oldest sciences, dating back thousands of years to ancient cultures that used the sky for navigation, timekeeping, and religious practices.
Early civilizations such as the Babylonians, Egyptians, and Chinese carefully observed the movements of celestial bodies to create calendars and predict natural events.
The Babylonians, over 5,000 years ago, recorded the positions of planets and stars, while the Egyptians aligned their pyramids with certain stars, demonstrating their knowledge of astronomy.
The Mayans developed a highly accurate calendar based on their detailed observations of the Sun, Moon, and Venus.
As societies advanced, so did their understanding of the cosmos. The Greeks introduced early scientific models,
such as Ptolemy’s geocentric theory, which placed Earth at the center of the universe.
Although later proven incorrect, this idea dominated for centuries until astronomers like Copernicus and Galileo challenged it.
</string>

    <string name="lesson3_title_2">The Scientific Revolution</string>
    <string name="lesson3_text_2">
The 16th and 17th centuries marked a turning point in astronomy. Nicolaus Copernicus proposed the heliocentric model,
suggesting that the Sun, not Earth, was at the center of the solar system. This idea was controversial at the time,
but it laid the foundation for modern astronomy. Later, Galileo Galilei used a telescope to make groundbreaking discoveries,
including the moons of Jupiter, sunspots, and the phases of Venus—all of which provided evidence that Earth was not the center of the universe.
Johannes Kepler introduced the laws of planetary motion, showing that planets move in elliptical orbits around the Sun.
Then, Isaac Newton’s law of gravity explained the forces governing planetary motion, further solidifying the heliocentric model.
This period, known as the Scientific Revolution, transformed astronomy from an observational practice into a precise science based on mathematics and physics.
</string>

    <string name="lesson3_title_3">Modern Astronomy and Space Exploration</string>
    <string name="lesson3_text_3">
With the development of powerful telescopes and space technology, our understanding of the universe has expanded dramatically.
The 20th century saw the rise of astrophysics, allowing scientists to study celestial objects in detail,
from distant galaxies to black holes. In 1929, Edwin Hubble discovered that the universe is expanding,
leading to the Big Bang theory. The invention of radio telescopes and space probes enabled us to explore space beyond Earth’s atmosphere.
The launch of the Hubble Space Telescope in 1990 provided breathtaking images of the cosmos, revealing the structure of galaxies and deep space phenomena.
Space agencies like NASA, ESA, and private companies continue to push the boundaries of space exploration,
searching for exoplanets, studying the origins of the universe, and even planning for human missions to Mars.
The journey of discovery, which began thousands of years ago with ancient astronomers gazing at the sky,
continues today as we unlock the secrets of the cosmos.
</string>


    <!--    lesson 4    -->
    <string name="lesson4_title">Tools of Astronomy: Telescopes &amp; Instruments</string>
    <string name="lesson4_title_1">The Power of Telescopes</string>
    <string name="lesson4_text_1">
        Telescopes are among the most important tools in astronomy.They allow scientists and sky watchers
        to observe distant objects in the universe by collecting and magnifying light.
        The first optical telescope was created in the early 1600s, and it revolutionized our view of the sky.
        Galileo Galilei was one of the first to use a telescope for astronomy,
        discovering the moons of Jupiter and the craters of the Moon. Today, telescopes come in many types and sizes,
        from small backyard telescopes to massive observatories.
        Optical telescopes use lenses or mirrors to collect visible light, while radio telescopes detect radio waves
        from space, allowing us to study things that can’t be seen with the eye.
        There are also telescopes designed for X-rays, infrared, ultraviolet, and gamma rays—each one revealing
        different features of stars, galaxies, and other cosmic phenomena.
    </string>

    <string name="lesson4_title_2">Ground-Based and Space Telescopes</string>
    <string name="lesson4_text_2">
        Most telescopes are located on Earth, often placed on mountain tops where the air is clearer
        and there’s less light pollution. However, the Earth\'s atmosphere can block or distort some types of light,
        which is why some telescopes are launched into space. Space telescopes, like the famous Hubble Space Telescope, give us a much clearer view of the universe by avoiding the interference of the atmosphere.
        Other space-based observatories, like the James Webb Space Telescope, look in infrared light and can peer through clouds of gas and dust to study the earliest galaxies.
        Together, ground-based and space telescopes work as powerful partners, helping astronomers learn more about the structure, age, and evolution of the universe.
</string>

    <string name="lesson4_title_3">Instruments That Expand Our Vision</string>
    <string name="lesson4_text_3">
        Besides telescopes, astronomers use many instruments to gather data and make discoveries. Spectrometers break light into its colors, or spectrum, revealing the composition and motion of stars and galaxies.
        Photometers measure the brightness of celestial objects, and CCD cameras (similar to those in smartphones) are used to capture digital images from telescopes. Computers and software now play a huge role in processing
        the vast amounts of data collected from observatories. Robotic telescopes and automated systems allow scientists to monitor the sky continuously and detect sudden events, like supernovae or asteroids.
        Thanks to these advanced tools and instruments, we can observe objects billions of light-years away, study planets orbiting other stars, and even search for signs of life beyond Earth.
    </string>



</resources>